Luca Luk

Product Designer

SUMMARY

Product Designer with **4+ years** of experience, specializing in **simplifying complex B2B workflows** for **large financial institution** with a **complex ecosystem** while collaborating with **20+ global clients** in **B2C agency** settings. Recognized for a **strong understanding of business and technical logic** as well as **coding skills** (HTML & CSS). Strong in **user research**, driving **measurable business outcomes** and effective **communication** with stakeholders and clients. Background in visual arts with a strong sense of **aesthetics**.

WORK HISTORY

Product Designer

Bank of China Hong Kong, Corporate Banking | Jul 2022 - Sep 2023

- Created the Mobile Cheque Deposit journey within an agile project, optimizing error scenarios to achieve a
 75.8% conversion rate, a 2.8× engagement boost, and a 43% improvement in cheque clearance rates.
- Revamped the corporate banking app for 130K+ customers by quantifying pain points with business impact, mapping complex user roles and workflows, and driving a 22% increase in downloads.
- Created the password reset journey to **resolve** a **top pain point** for users and staff, **serving 5,023 users** in six months and **reducing support costs** equivalent to **two full-time staff**.
- Designed features for a **staff workbench**, conducted **15+ stakeholder interviews** to identify pain points and **tested prototypes** to **shift focus from costly tools** to addressing policy-driven inefficiencies.
- Collaborated cross-functionally with business analyst, product, development and compliance to create an all-inone platform, developing a unified blueprint for seamless customer journeys.

Product Designer

Branding Records, Global Agency | Nov 2020 - Jul 2022

- Restructured the **information architecture** of a **200+ page** education network, **raised admission inquiries by 32%** by **optimizing navigation** and **content strategy** while creating a **design system** using **customizable templates**.
- Designed **brand website** for alfred24, analyzing user demographics and behavior with **Google Analytics**. Insights drove a **6.3% conversion rate** and a **28% increase in unique page views** within the first month.
- Led an **interactive campaign** for a crypto platform (Phemex), achieving a **2% sign-up conversion** rate (exceeding the 0.2–1.4% industry average) and a **67% increase in unique page views** within the first month.
- Collaborated with developers on web projects, resolving technical constraints with creative UX solutions; developed websites independently using Webflow.

Web Designer

Luca Luk, Design Consultancy | Jan 2019 - Oct 2020

• Designed high-converting landing pages and marketing materials, increasing sales by 375% for a healthy sports drink through strategic content optimization and compelling visuals.

Design and Production Lead

Century Culture, Startup Publisher | Sep 2015 - Oct 2018

• Revamped the **e-commerce site** for parents and children by optimizing navigation and UI, resulting in a **24%** increase in sales. Managed a team of five to deliver visual materials for **100+ publications**.

EDUCATION

UI/UX Designer Advanced Diploma (Co-op)

Cornerstone International Community College of Canada, Vancouver | Expected Sep 2024

Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO)

Scrum Alliance | Jun 2023

Bachelor of Visual Arts (Design & Crafts)

Hong Kong Baptist University | Sep 2011 - Aug 2015

SKILLS

Research & Strategy: Concept Testing, User Interviews, Usability Testing, Journey Mapping, UX Blueprints

Interaction Design: Prototyping, Wireframing, Mockups, Storyboards, Visual Design, Accessibility, Design Systems

Tools & Technical: Figma, FigJam, Google Analytics, Miro, Dovetail, Adobe Creative Suite, HTML, CSS

Soft Skills: Collaboration, Agile Methodology, Stakeholder Engagement, Workshop Facilitation, Storytelling

AWARD

Outstanding Project Award — Oct 2024

Cornerstone International Community College of Canada

Rising Star Award — Apr 2023

Bank of China Corporate Banking